<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Processing on La1r</title><link>https://la1r.com/docs/technical-setup/data-processing/</link><description>Recent content in Data Processing on La1r</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://la1r.com/docs/technical-setup/data-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>(Streaming) Analytics</title><link>https://la1r.com/docs/technical-setup/data-processing/streaming-analyitics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://la1r.com/docs/technical-setup/data-processing/streaming-analyitics/</guid><description>Streaming analyitics as default Since La1r is applying a Kappa architecture (see conceptual setup for more details on this), it is essential that as many of it's processes occur in a streaming fasion. This also includes all the performed analytics. Streaming analytics brings new considerations, such as messaging ordering and quality of prefix data. Since these concepts are handled out-of-the-box (OOTB) in Spark 2.x, Spark 2.x is considered as the default method of applying streaming analytics.</description></item><item><title>(Streaming) Transformations</title><link>https://la1r.com/docs/technical-setup/data-processing/streaming-transformations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://la1r.com/docs/technical-setup/data-processing/streaming-transformations/</guid><description>Streaming transformations A serveral scenario's in la1r, a (streaming) transformation needs to be made to get the raw streaming data in the structured shape. This is often the case because there are several integrations with commercial-of-the-shelf (COTS) products which do not follow the same structured model.
Nifi and GUI as default Transformations should be easily adjustable to quickly fit the changing data needs. For this reason Nifi is used as the default tool for (streaming) data transformations.</description></item></channel></rss>